BERNARD OTIENO OMONDI

P.O. Box 21293. 00100, GPO, Nairobi Phone: +254 722 468019 Email: bomondy@gmail.com

QUALITY & PROCESS IMPROVEMENT OFFICER

Continual quality and process improvement in the setting of healthcare provision is not only my specialty, but also my passion. I have more than nine years of experience in this field. Attention to detail, delivering results within defined timelines and the ability to work collaboratively across the board are the attributes that I have honed over the years to be successful in this field. I have an appreciation of patient services, patient safety and support and service delivery. I am fluent in English and Swahili, and a beginner in French.

Planned Projects:

- 1. Kaizen Implementation across Functions Team Member Certified Kaizen Practitioner (CKP).
 - i. Equipped with skills in Business Process Improvement using Process Mapping, Swim Lane Mapping, OPL and other frameworks.
 - ii. Implementation of 5S.
- 2. Joint Commission International Accreditation Team Member

Completed Projects:

- 1. Customization, Implementation, Staff Training and Administration of Q-Pulse Team Leader
- 2. ISO Certification Transition from ISO 22000:2005 to ISO 22000:2018 Team Member
- 3. ISO Certification Upgrade from HACCP Accreditation to ISO 22000:2005 Team Member
- 4. ISO Certification Transition from ISO 14001:2004 to ISO 14001:2015 Team Member
- 5. ISO Certification Transition from ISO 9001:2008 to ISO 9001:2015 Team Member
- 6. Process Mapping & Documentation of Policies, Procedures, Protocols etc. for Catering Department Team Leader

AREAS OF PROFICIENCY

- ISO 9001:2015 ImplementationISO 22000:2018 Lead Auditor
- Food Safety Training
- ISO Documentation
- Automated ISO Compliance
- Occupational Safety & Health

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

THE NAIROBI HOSPITAL, KENYA QUALITY IMPROVEMENT OFFICER (2010 TO APRIL 2021) & OUTSOURCED SERVICES COORDINATOR (2006 TO 2010)

2006 - 2021

- Facilitation of ISO 22000:2018, ISO 9001:2015 & ISO 14001:2015 implementation across the Hospital with emphasis on ISO 22000:2018 in Catering Unit (catering for production and service of food to an average of 300 patients, 120 students and 500 staff members daily).
- Facilitate ISO Training for staff on a Quarterly basis and as and when necessary for new staff.
- Facilitate annual evaluation of legal compliance e.g., Food Handlers' Medical Examination requirement.
- Provide support to Marketing & Customer Service department for the management of customer/client feedback and complaints.
- Preparation of training material using predominantly Microsoft PowerPoint and dissemination of training in person and virtually using Microsoft Teams. Facilitate the use of automated computer application (Q-Pulse application) to plan, schedule and invite staff for training and management of all training records, certificates and skill checks.
- Plan, schedule, conduct, report and make follow up on all supplier audits annually.

- Implement Semi-annual evaluation ISO audits of food safety management system and evaluation of the effectiveness of the corrective actions where nonconformities are found.
- Prepare and present to Senior Management Team, the Management Review Report for Food Safety Management System, Quality Management System and Environmental Management System twice annually.
- Prepare, facilitate and coordinate with the Certification Body for the Surveillance and Recertification audits. Lead the implementation of any identified areas of improvement and non-conformities.
- Documentation of Process Flow Charts, Standard Operating Procedures, Food Safety Manuals, Food safety objectives and other necessary documentation such as checklists and forms.
- Facilitate verification and validation tests.
- Schedule and implement Occupational Safety & Health workplace inspections and OSH Committee Meetings.
- Facilitate the use of an automated computer application (Q-Pulse application) administration, User training, management briefing, liaison with ICT department and Q-Pulse vendor for system updates, upgrades, training and troubleshooting. Q-Pulse is an effective computer application for managing continual quality improvement.

JOHNSON CONTROLS PTY SITE SERVICES COORDINATOR

2000 - 2006

- SITE SERVICES COURDINATUR
- Management of outsourced services (non-core to the business or providing support services).
- Develop service level agreements (SLA) and then evaluate the service providers against the defined SLA.
- Preparation of annual budgets and preparation of monthly and quarterly management reports.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

- Certified Kaizen Practitioner (CKP) Kaizen Institute Nairobi, 2019
- Certificate in ISO 9001: 2015, ISO 14001:2015 & ISO 22000:2005 Implementation & Auditing, KEBS, 2007, 2009 & 2015-2016
- Bachelor of Science Degree, Egerton University, Nakuru, Kenya, 1998
- Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, St. Mary's School, Yala, Kenya, 1992
- Basic Life Support Certificate, Cicely McDonnell School of Nursing, Nairobi, Kenya, 2014

MEMBERSHIP & COMMITTEES

- The Nairobi Hospital: Continuous Quality Improvement Committee, ISO Implementation & Auditing
- Certified Kaizen Practitioners
- Occupational Safety & Health Committee
- National Quality Institute (Kenya Bureau of Standards)
- Continuous Quality Improvement Consultant; Regional Centre for Quality of Healthcare, Makerere University, Uganda.

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Susan Gachihi **Support Services Administrator**The Nairobi Hospital
Tel. +254 722 884709

<u>susangachihi@nbihosp.org</u>

Wycliffe Alwal
Manager, Data Centre
Family Bank
Tel. +254 733 700351
walwal@familybank.co.ke

Fredrick Asige **Lead Radiotherapist**The Nairobi Hospital
Tel. +254 721 474666
fredrickasige@nbihosp.org